# **Talukder Mahboob Rasul**

Flat: 6/B, Mitali Palace II, 68/1 Dilkushabag

Savar, Dhaka-1340 Mobile: +8801711085041

Email: rabbi.mahboob@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rabbi-mahboob/



## **Professional Summary**

I am an HR enthusiast with MBA & BBA in HRM, having almost 3 years of working experience in different sectors. Currently, I am working at the Corporate Office of one of the leading apparel manufacturing organizations in the country as an Executive in the HR department.

# Experiences

**Ananta Companies** (Corporate Head Office)

November 2019 - Continuing

**Executive, Human Resources** 

(Responsible for Organizational Development and Policy Making)

## **Job Responsibilities:**

- 1. Responsible for policy development and research work to ensure cost effectiveness of the organization.
- 2. Support the development and implementation of HR initiatives and systems.
- 3. Assist in recruitment process (Taking assessments and conducting interviews).
- 4. To prepare Quota & Organogram of all factories.
- 5. To prepare different forms and formats.
- 6. ERP development and following up the progress with ICT.
- 7. Creating and implementing effective onboarding plans.
- 8. Preparing final settlement bills.
- 9. Managing foreign employees' leave, preparing their legal documents and manual salary bills.
- 10. Creating team building activities such as arranging meetings, compiling meeting agendas etc.
- 11. Investigating suspicious activities (frequent absenteeism, irregularity in punching etc.) of employees.
- 12. Communicating and coordinating with external parties to make deals (Memorandum of Understanding).
- 13. Managing different types of HR database.
- 14. Preparing different kind of reports that are required by the management.
- 15. Following up and coordinating all the function/factory HRs to support and monitor their progress in any assignment.
- 16. Preparing monthly manpower analysis report (Factory wise).
- 17. Any other duties and responsibilities assigned by the management.

**ACI Limited** (Pharmaceuticals Head Office)

July 2017 - July 2018

**Coordination Officer, Medical Service Department** 

(Responsible to take care of all the departmental administrative activities)

## **Grameenphone Limited**

December 2013 - December 2014

# **Junior Apprentice, Contact Center**

(Responsible to provide smooth and flawless customer service over phone, web chat and email)

## **Education**

Master of Business Administration (MBA) Jahangirnagar University

> Human Resource Management (HRM) Result: 3.02; Passing Year: 2019

**Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)** ASA University Bangladesh

> Human Resource Management (HRM) Result: 2.97; Passing Year: 2016

Mirja Golam Hafiz College; Board: Dhaka **Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)** :

> Concentration: Business Studies Result: 4.20; Passing Year: 2011

Secondary School Certificate (SSC) BPATC School & College; Board: Dhaka :

> Concentration: Business Studies Result: 4.69; Passing Year: 2009

#### **Extracurricular Activities**

 Worked with Dr. Rumana Dowla and Rubaba Dowla to manage one of their CSR projects (2017-18)

Bangladesh Palliative & Support Care Foundation, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

- Participated in Social Business Plan and Management Competition. (2014) ASA University, Dhaka, Bangladesh
- Actively organized numerous social events and student orientation programs. (2014-16) ASA University, Dhaka, Bangladesh
- Organized "Food for Poor" project for slum areas in Dhaka, Bangladesh. (2015)
- Active member of Career & Language Club. (2014-16)
  - ASA University, Dhaka, Bangladesh
- Innovation Award for participating in business week. (2013) ASA University, Dhaka, Bangladesh
- Participated in Book Reading Competition. (2014) British Council, Dhaka, Bangladesh

# Language Proficiency

Bengali: Fluent both in speaking and writing. English: Excellent both in speaking and writing.

## **Computer Literacy**

- ✓ Comfortable with almost all types of Operating Systems.
- ✓ Sound in using Microsoft Office Tools (MS Word, MS Excel, Power Point, MS Publisher).
- ✓ Good at photo editing with Adobe Photoshop CS6.
- ✓ Good at video editing with Wondershare Filmora.
- ✓ Good Knowledge over Internet Browsing, Social Networking, Emailing, etc.
- ✓ Typing speed 42 WPM.

## **Exclusive Interest**

• Playing Ukulele, Riding Motorcycle and Cycle, Travelling, Editing Photos and Videos.

## **Personal Information**

Name : Talukder Mahboob Rasul Father's name : MD. Ratan Hossain Talukder

Mother's name : Keya Talukder
Date of birth : December 15, 1994

Nationality : Bangladeshi

Religion : Islam

Marital Status : Unmarried

Height : 5'5" Blood Group : O (+ve)

## References

Tanveer Rahman Md. Ataur Rahman

Assistant General Manager Manager

Human Resource Department Human Resource Department

Ananta Companies (Corporate Office) Ananta Companies (Corporate Office)

Mobile: +8801713199500 Mobile: +8801713199544